Guide to the Camp Kinderland Records TAM.439
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IX: Photographic Materials, 1924-2010, 15.5 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons, 1 flat box, 2 oversized flat boxes, and 16 manuscript boxes; 4.18 Megabytes in 35 files
  - Glass Plate Negatives
    - Bunk 18, Group 4 with "Workers' children against war" banner, 1935; cuid13408 (Box 44)
    - Bunk 19, 1935; cuid13409 (Box 44)
    - Bunk 19, Garden workers, 1935; cuid13410 (Box 44)
    - Bunk 1-girls, 1935; cuid13411 (Box 46)
    - Bunk 2, Group 1, 1935; cuid13412 (Box 46)
    - Bunk 20, Group 1, 1935; cuid13413 (Box 46)
    - Bunk 21-22, 1935; cuid13414 (Box 45)
    - Bunk 23-24, Group 3 with anti-war banner., 1935; cuid13415 (Box 46)
    - Bunk 3, Group 1, 1935; cuid13416 (Box 44)
    - Bunk 4, Group 2, 1935; cuid13417 (Box 46)
    - Bunk 5, Group 2 with Boycott Nazi Olympics banner, 1935; cuid13418 (Box 46)
    - Bunk 6, Cabin 25, 1935; cuid13419 (Box 46)
    - Bunk 6, Group 2, 1935; cuid13420 (Box 47)
    - Bunk 7, 1935; cuid13421 (Box 46)
    - Bunk 9, Group 3, 1935; cuid13422 (Box 44)
    - Bunks 27-28 with "We Demand the Soviet Union be invited to the Olympics" banner, 1935; cuid13423 (Box 44)
    - Bunks 29-30 with Olympic protest banners, 1935; cuid13424 (Box 44)
    - Bunks 29-30 with Olympic protest banners, 1935; cuid13425 (Box 44)
    - Bunks 35-36, 1935; cuid13426 (Box 44)
    - Bureau of the Anti-War Congress, 1935; cuid13427 (Box 44)
    - Cabin 28, 1935; cuid13428 (Box 47)
    - Campers drinking water, 1930-1939; cuid13429 (Box 44)
    - Children leaving on Friday, 1935; cuid13430 (Box 45)
    - Children leaving on Friday, 1935; cuid13431 (Box 47)
    - Children leaving on Friday, 1935; cuid13432 (Box 47)
    - Children playing instruments, 1935; cuid13433 (Box 44)
    - Children playing instruments, 1935; cuid13434 (Box 44)
    - Children's art installation, 1935; cuid13435 (Box 46)
    - Cleanliness Bulletin, undated; cuid13436 (Box 44)
    - Cleanliness Bulletin, undated; cuid13437 (Box 44)
    - Counselors, 1935; cuid13438 (Box 44)
    - Counselors, 1935; cuid13439 (Box 44)
    - Counselors, 1935; cuid13440 (Box 44)
    - Counselors and campers by cars, 1935; cuid13441 (Box 44)
    - Dance Group, 1935; cuid13442 (Box 45)
    - Dance Group, 1935; cuid13443 (Box 47)
    - Demonstration, 1935; cuid13444 (Box 46)
    - Demonstration, 1935; cuid13445 (Box 44)
    - Demonstration, 1935; cuid13446 (Box 45)
    - Demonstration, 1935; cuid13447 (Box 45)
    - Demonstration, 1935; cuid13448 (Box 45)
    - Demonstration, 1935; cuid13449 (Box 47)
    - Dining hall, 1935; cuid13450 (Box 46)
    - Dining Room, 1935; cuid13451 (Box 44)
    - Dining room workers, 1935; cuid13452 (Box 44)
    - Directors Meeting, 1935; cuid13453 (Box 45)
    - Erecting the Kinderland sign on the main entrance, 1930-1939; cuid13454 (Box 45)
    - Erecting the Kinderland sign on the main entrance, 1930-1939; cuid13455 (Box 45)
    - Erecting the Kinderland sign on the main entrance, 1930-1939; cuid13456 (Box 45)
    - Exercising, 1935; cuid13457 (Box 44)
    - Exercising, 1935; cuid13458 (Box 44)
    - Exercising, 1935; cuid13459 (Box 44)
    - Exercising, 1935; cuid13460 (Box 44)
    - Exercising, 1935; cuid13461 (Box 44)
    - Exercising, 1935; cuid13462 (Box 45)
    - Female campers with anti-war posters, 1935; cuid13463 (Box 44)
    - Fifth Group, 1935; cuid13464 (Box 44)
    - First Class, 1935; cuid13465 (Box 44)
    - First Group, 1935; cuid13466 (Box 46)
    - First Group, 1935; cuid13467 (Box 46)
    - First National Teachers' Conference, 1935; cuid13468 (Box 45)
    - First National Teachers' Conference, 1935; cuid13469 (Box 45)
    - First National Teachers' Conference, 1935; cuid13470 (Box 47)
    - Fourth Group, 1935; cuid13471 (Box 44)
    - French United Front, Anti-war Congress, 1935; cuid13472 (Box 44)
    - French United Front, Anti-war Congress, 1935; cuid13473 (Box 45)
    - French United Front, Anti-war Congress, 1935; cuid13474 (Box 45)
    - French United Front, Anti-war Congress, 1935; cuid13475 (Box 45)
    - Friday morning, 1935; cuid13476 (Box 45)
    - Garden work, Bunk 19, 1935; cuid13477 (Box 46)
    - Girl in front of children's dining room, 1930-1939; cuid13478 (Box 46)
    - Group 1. Joseph Cutler banner., 1935; cuid13479 (Box 46)
    - Group 10, Bunk 5 (gardening group), 1935; cuid13480 (Box 46)
    - Group 2, 1935; cuid13481 (Box 44)
    - Group 2, 1935; cuid13482 (Box 45)
    - Group 2, 1935; cuid13483 (Box 45)
    - Group 2, Bunk 33-34, 1935; cuid13484 (Box 45)
    - Group 3, Bunk 6, 8, 9, 19, 21, 23, 1935; cuid13485 (Box 46)
    - Group 3, Bunks 6, 8, 9, 19, 21, 23, 1935; cuid13486 (Box 45)
    - Group 4, 1936; cuid13487 (Box 45)
    - Group 5, 1935; cuid13488 (Box 46)
    - Group 5, Bunks 10, 11, 12, 1935; cuid13489 (Box 44)
    - Group 8, Bunk 3 (girls doing arts and crafts), 1935; cuid13490 (Box 46)
    - Group in front of entrance, 1935; cuid13491 (Box 44)
    - Group in front of entrance, 1935; cuid13492 (Box 45)
    - Group in front of Lenin Monument, 1935; cuid13493 (Box 45)
    - Group of boys with a "Blacks and Whites United" Sign, 1930-1939; cuid13494 (Box 44)
    - Group portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13495 (Box 46)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13496 (Box 44)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13497 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13498 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13499 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13500 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13501 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13502 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13503 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13504 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13505 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13506 (Box 45)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13507 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13508 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13509 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13510 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13511 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13512 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13513 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13514 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13515 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13516 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13517 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13518 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13519 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13520 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13521 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13522 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13523 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13524 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13525 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13526 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13527 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13528 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait, 1935; cuid13529 (Box 47)
    - Group Portrait with Hammer and Sickle, 1935; cuid13530 (Box 44)
    - Hinsdale Workers Club at Camp Kinderland, 1935; cuid36853 (Box 49)
    - In front of campfire, 1930-1939; cuid13531 (Box 45)
    - In the bushes near the Infirmary, 1930-1939; cuid13532 (Box 47)
    - Kindergarden, 1935; cuid13533 (Box 46)
    - Kindergarden, 1935; cuid13534 (Box 46)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935; cuid13535 (Box 44)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935; cuid13536 (Box 44)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935; cuid13537 (Box 44)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935; cuid13538 (Box 44)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935; cuid13539 (Box 44)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935; cuid13540 (Box 44)
    - Kinderland Choir, undated; cuid13541 (Box 44)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935; cuid13542 (Box 44)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935; cuid13543 (Box 45)
    - Kinderland entrance, 1930-1939; cuid13544 (Box 46)
    - Kinderland office, 1935; cuid13545 (Box 44)
    - Laundry Room, 1930-1939; cuid13546 (Box 45)
    - Lesson with Gina Medem, 1935; cuid13547 (Box 44)
    - Lesson with Gina Medem, 1935; cuid13548 (Box 44)
    - Library, 1935; cuid13549 (Box 44)
    - Listening to lecture, 1935; cuid13550 (Box 44)
    - Literary corner, 1935; cuid13551 (Box 44)
    - Literature Booth, 1935; cuid13552 (Box 44)
    - Lowlies, 1935; cuid13553 (Box 46)
    - LSNR Meeting, 1935; cuid13554 (Box 44)
    - LSNR Meeting, 1935; cuid13555 (Box 45)
    - Man and Girl, 1930-1939; cuid13556 (Box 47)
    - Man and Woman, 1930-1949; cuid13557 (Box 46)
    - Man and Woman, 1930-1939; cuid13558 (Box 45)
    - Man and Woman, 1930-1939; cuid13559 (Box 45)
    - Man and Woman, 1930-1939; cuid13560 (Box 45)
    - Man and Woman, 1930-1939; cuid13561 (Box 45)
    - Man and Woman, 1930-1939; cuid13562 (Box 47)
    - Man and Woman, 1930-1939; cuid13563 (Box 47)
    - Man using a water fountain, 1935; cuid13564 (Box 45)
    - Medal Forum, 1935; cuid13565 (Box 47)
    - Models of Buildings, 1935; cuid36852 (Box 49)
    - Morning Salute, 1935; cuid13566 (Box 44)
    - Morning Salute, 1935; cuid13567 (Box 44)
    - Morning Salute, 1935; cuid13568 (Box 44)
    - Morning Salute, 1935; cuid13569 (Box 44)
    - Morning Salute, 1936; cuid13570 (Box 45)
    - Morning Salute, 1936; cuid13571 (Box 45)
    - Morning Salute, 1936; cuid13572 (Box 45)
    - Morning Salute, 1936; cuid13573 (Box 45)
    - Morning Salute, 1936; cuid13574 (Box 45)
    - Morning Salute, 1936; cuid13575 (Box 47)
    - Mural, 1935; cuid13576 (Box 44)
    - Office Staff, 1935; cuid13577 (Box 46)
    - Office Staff, 1935; cuid13578 (Box 45)
    - Office Staff, 1935; cuid13579 (Box 45)
    - Open Forum, 1935; cuid13580 (Box 47)
    - Open Forum, 1935; cuid13581 (Box 47)
    - Open Forum, 1935; cuid13582 (Box 47)
    - Open Forum, 1935; cuid13583 (Box 47)
    - Parents by the entrance, 1935; cuid13584 (Box 46)
    - Partially exposed or damaged negative, circa 1935; cuid13585 (Box 44)
    - Primary School, 1935; cuid13586 (Box 47)
    - Primary School, 1935; cuid13587 (Box 47)
    - Red Square Building, 1930-1939; cuid13588 (Box 45)
    - Registration in Camp Kinderland office, 1935; cuid13589 (Box 45)
    - Robert Minor at Camp Kinderland, 1935; cuid13590 (Box 44)
    - Robert Minor at Camp Kinderland, 1935; cuid13591 (Box 44)
    - Second American Youth Congress, 1935; cuid13592 (Box 44)
    - Second Group, 1935; cuid13593 (Box 46)
    - Shot of a group of school children at Camp Kinderland, 1935; cuid13594 (Box 45)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13595 (Box 45)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13596 (Box 45)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13597 (Box 45)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13598 (Box 45)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13599 (Box 45)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13600 (Box 45)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13601 (Box 47)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13602 (Box 47)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13603 (Box 47)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13604 (Box 47)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13605 (Box 47)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13606 (Box 47)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930-1939; cuid13607 (Box 47)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13608 (Box 44)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13609 (Box 44)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13610 (Box 44)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13611 (Box 45)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13612 (Box 47)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13613 (Box 47)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13614 (Box 47)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13615 (Box 47)
    - Study Group, 1935; cuid13616 (Box 44)
    - Suitcases, 1935; cuid13617 (Box 45)
    - Teaching Class, 1935; cuid13618 (Box 45)
    - The unveiling of the Lenin monument, 1935; cuid13619 (Box 45)
    - The unveiling of the Lenin monument, 1935; cuid13620 (Box 45)
    - The unveiling of the Lenin monument, 1935; cuid13621 (Box 45)
    - The unveiling of the Lenin monument, 1935; cuid13622 (Box 45)
    - Three Boys Outside, circa 1930s-1940s; cuid13623 (Box 46)
    - Three Women, 1930-1939; cuid13624 (Box 47)
    - Two Men, 1930-1939; cuid13625 (Box 45)
    - Two Men, 1930-1939; cuid13626 (Box 45)
    - Two Women, 1930-1939; cuid13627 (Box 47)
    - Waterfront, 1935; cuid13628 (Box 45)
    - Woman, 1930-1939; cuid13629 (Box 44)
  - Photographs and Negatives
    - 57 negatives of Camp Kinderland, mostly group portraits and images from events, 1938-1943; cuid13630 (Box 46)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1930-1932 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1936; cuid36914 (Box 18, Folder 5, Box 35, Folder 9, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1937; cuid36915 (Box 18, Folder 6, Box 19, Folder 1, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_6)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1938; cuid36916 (Box 19, Folder 2, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_7)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1939; cuid36917 (Box 19, Folder 3, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_8)
    - Camp Life (Oversize Reproductions), circa 1930-1949; cuid13636; 2 folders (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1940; cuid36918 (Box 19, Folder 4, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_9)
    - Camp Life (Oversize Reproductions), circa 1940-1949; cuid13635; 2 folders (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1941; cuid36919 (Box 20, Folder 1, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_10)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1942; cuid36920 (Box 20, Folder 2, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_11)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1953-1958 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 4-5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Camp Life (Oversize Reproductions), 1979-1980 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1982-1985 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1987-1989 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Photograph Albums, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Group Shots, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Photograph Albums, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
    - Photograph Albums, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1992-1993 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Photograph Albums, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 2-4)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1994-1995 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1996-1997 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Trip to Cuba, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 2003-2004 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Group Shot (Oversize), 2004-2008; cuid13641 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 2006-2010 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Itzkowitz, Ben (Oversize), undated; cuid13643; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Slides
    - Slides, circa 1930-1939; cuid13664 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Slides, 1940-1951; cuid13665 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Slides, circa 1960-1969; cuid13666 (Box 31, Folder 5-7)
    - Slides, circa 1970-1979; cuid13667 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Slides, circa 1980-1989 (Box 31, Folder 9, Box 35, Folder 1-6)
    - Slides, 1990-1992 (Box 35, Folder 7)
- Series X: Audiovisual Materials, 1951-2005; 36.25 Linear Feet in 3 film cans, 1 record carton, 2 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, and 1 card box; 62 VHS; 6 CDs; 4 DVD-R; 2 sound tape reels; 2 film reels; 6 audiocassettes; 10 VHS-C; 6 Hi8; 14.6 Gigabytes in 27 files
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains oral history interviews with former campers, promotional videos for the camp, and recordings of camp plays and other activities on a variety of audiovisual formats.
  - Camp Spruce Hill Hi-Lights, Parts 1-4, undated; cuid15040; 4 film reels 16mm (Box Digitized Access Copies, File tam439_cuid15040_1, tam439_cuid15040_2, tam439_cuid15040_3, tam439_cuid15040_4, Box Shared Tamiment 133, Reel cuid15040_1, Reel cuid15040_2, Reel cuid15040_3, Reel cuid15040_4)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Source format: 8mm film, silent, color
  - Yiddish Lessons, undated; cuid13671 (Film cuid13671, Reel cuid13671, Box Digitized Access Copies, File tam439_cuid13671)
    Format: 16mm film [Release Print], Color, Sound
  - 25th Anniversary Celebration (possibly with Anna Louise Strong), 1948-1949 (Box Shared Tamiment 166, Film 2011.110)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Accretion, 2011.
  - Nigendl: A Jewish Family Portrait, 1951; cuid13672 (Film cuid13672, Reel cuid13672, Box Digitized Access Copies, File tam349_cuid13672)
  - Nigendl: A Jewish Family Portrait, 1951; cuid13673 (Film cuid13673, Reel cuid13673, Box Digitized Access Copies, File tam439_cuid13673)
  - Oral History Interviews with Former Campers, Index and Questions, 1987-2005; cuid13654 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Oral History Interviews, 2005; cuid36921 (Box 36, Vhs 439.0001-439.0008, Box Shared Tamiment 159, Cd 439.0005, Box 41, Audiocassette 439.0066, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_3)
  - Suller, Elsie Retirement Party and Memorial, 1990-2001 (Box 36, Vhs 439.0009-0014, Box 41, Vhs-c 439.0073-439.0074, Box 42, Vhs-c 439.0077)
  - Segal, Edith Memorial, 1997 (Box 37, Vhs 439.0015-439.0019, Box 42, Vhs-c 439.0078-439.0083, Box Shared Tamiment 159, Cd 439.0006)
  - Off-Season Events, 1960-2004; cuid36922 (Box 37, Vhs 439.0020-439.0024, 439.0026, Box 41, 8mm film reel 439.0062, Quarter inch audio reel 439.0064, 439.0089, Box Shared Tamiment 159, Cd 439.0003-439.0004, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_2)
    Includes Passover celebration (1981), trip to Cuba (2000), and protest march (2004), among others.
  - Promotional Videos, undated (Box 37, Vhs 439.0025, 439.0027)
  - Camp Performances and Events, 1969-2003; cuid36923 (Box 38, Vhs 439.0028-439.0040, Box 39, Vhs 439.0041-439.0052, Box 40, Vhs 439.0053-439.0061, 439.0067, Box 41, Quarter inch audio reel 439.0065, Box 42, Vhs-c 439.0075, Hi8 439.0076, 439.0084-439.0088, Box Shared Tamiment 159, Dvd 439.0007-439.010, Audiocassette 439.0068-439.0069, 439.0072, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_4)
    Includes camper performances of Fiddler on the Roof and Finian's Rainbow, and camp events, such as Visiting Day, among others.
  - Davis, Ossie Performance, 1965; cuid36924 (Box 41, 8mm film reel 439.0063, Box Shared Tamiment 159, Cd 439.0001, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_439_ER_1)
  - McCune, Mariann, "Camp Kinderland," WNYC, undated (Box 41, Audiocassette 439.0070)
  - Williams, Helene Sings Songs of Conscience (Songs to Poems by Edith Segal), 1991 (Box 41, Audiocassette 439.0071)
- Series XI: Objects, 1954-1999; 2.9 Linear Feet in 1 oversized flat box, 1 manuscript box, and 1 record carton
  This series contains artifacts from, and collected by, Camp Kinderland, such as a bandanna with the camp's logo and a Chinese flag.
  - Bandana and Button, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Banners with Russian Writing, undated; cuid13651 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Flag of China, undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Soviet Union Welcomes You! Poster, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Seal Press, 1954; cuid13670 (Box 48)
- Series XII: Archived Websites, April 2012-ongoing; 4 websites in 4 archived websites.
  Crawling of the Camp Kinderland website began in 2012. The website contains news and event listings; scholarship funds; camper and parent resources; sample weekly camp schedules; their camp programming; and information about renting their facilities. Other materials on the website include a community survey conducted in 2013; booklet on their arts activism festival; curriculum for their secular Jewish school Shule; alumni documentation; United Council of Resistance (UnCOR) campaigns; and annivesary celebrations. The website also contains issues of their newsletter dating back to 2012. The website underwent a redesign in 2014.
  The series also contains websites related to Camp Kinderland staffing information and the digital album, "Singing With Ira." The album was made to honor the legacy of Ira Coleman-Palansky, their Program Director, who died in 2024.
  Arrangement
  Series arranged by date of capture.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of campkinderland.org and campkinderland.bandcamp.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Crawl was expanded to include Google documents and the Constant Contact subdomain.
- Series XIII: 2017 Accretion, 1937-2014; 1.2 Linear Feet in 1 half manuscript box and 1 flat box
  This accretion to the Camp Kindeland Records consists of photocopies of photographs of campers in the 1940s, a brief history of the camp and its historical context, a list of individuals affiliated with Camp Kinderland who participated in the Spanish Civil War as part of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade or who died in World War II, a photocopy of a letter written in Yiddish on a handkerchief along with an English translation, and a survey map of the grounds.
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  - History of Camp Kinderland, 2011 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - List of Individuals Affiliated with Camp Kinderland in Spanish Civil War or World War II, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - "Handkerchief Letter", 1937 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - White Salute Photograph, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - News Bulletin, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Reunion Programs, 1979-2014 (Box 43, Folder 6-8)
  - Song Book, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1943-1944 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Survey Map, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 1)